<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rheea Mukherjee on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/author/rheea-mukherjee/</link><description>Recent content in Rheea Mukherjee on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 01:29:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/author/rheea-mukherjee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Girl Who Kissed Shah Rukh Khan – by Rheea Mukherjee</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/07/p577/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 01:29:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/07/p577/</guid><description>Chances are you’ve seen my girlfriend. In that tangerine spaghetti strapped shirt. Her hand cupping the stubble on Shah Rukh Khan’s chin. Her shiny straight hair hitting the sharpness of her jaw, her lips puckered and pushed out to meet his gaunt cheeks. Shah Rukh stared back at the camera, poker-fucking straight. If you looked closely enough, you’ll see her eyelashes have too much mascara on them. Clumps of hair in black goop.</description></item><item><title>Keeping Pace – by Rheea Mukherjee</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/01/p249/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:10:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/01/p249/</guid><description>I was the first woman in his life, she, the most recent. Apart from him, the other thing we had in common was running. I’d finished one full and three half marathons. She was attempting her first 10k. The type of distance that becomes an accessory. She was the type of artist that makes a living out of being one. Her 10k goal was an urban layer of achievement that adds nicely to a personality.</description></item><item><title>Transit for Beginners – by Rheea Mukherjee</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/08/p63/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 10:15:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/08/p63/</guid><description>I met him at Changi airport. After a seven hour flight from Tokyo, preceded by an eleven hour flight to Tokyo. My breath was stale and my deodorant had long since given up. Changi was a festival, packed with dazzling places to shop at and strange luxurious things to do. Showers with towel service, a spa, a movie theater, a twenty-four hour gym, and even a swimming pool in case the urge to swim struck while you were in between flights.</description></item></channel></rss>