<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ranjani Murali on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/author/ranjani-murali/</link><description>Recent content in Ranjani Murali on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 03:31:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/author/ranjani-murali/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Picked Up Ghazals – by Ranjani Murali</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/10/p768/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 03:31:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/10/p768/</guid><description>(To access the poem in its original format, please click here)
***
_I’m going to quit school and join the boy scouts.
_
He ran away when he was fifteen. The sleeper trains used to have green leather seats.
The news flash read: Traps are being laid to capture innocent animals and to enslave unsuspecting natives.
When the lodge owner asked for his address, he walked out.
Outings during June were fantastic with a good strong swell and off shore winds.</description></item><item><title>On Lighting Up – by Ranjani Murali</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/12/p520/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 14:54:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/12/p520/</guid><description>That day, we watched Patchaikili Muthucharam, studying the contours of Sarathkumar’s triceps, while he exclaimed all the while semma body I’m telling you it’s aatukaal soup with extra blood. I had no frame of reference; the only blood I sought was sparse every month and irrevocably stained the satin underwear I bought at the export store in Pondicherry. When I had gone to buy them, the saleswomen giggled uncontrollably and adjusted their dupattas when I told them to let him into the trial room.</description></item></channel></rss>