<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>C1 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/issue/c1/</link><description>Recent content in C1 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 06:40:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/issue/c1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Four Poems</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/07/p751/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 06:40:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/07/p751/</guid><description>To preserve the format of these poems, we have made them available in a downloadable Pdf.
To open the Pdf, please click here</description></item><item><title>Two Poems</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/07/p749/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 06:37:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/07/p749/</guid><description>**When Shammi Kapoor slides down the snow
**
in Junglee, shouting ‘Yahoo’, they tell you it’s Kashmir
but it is actually Kufri, near Shimla.
When Ranbir Kapoor climbs up the snow
in YJHD, all moon-struck, they tell you it’s Manali
but it is actually Gulmarg, in Kashmir.
So we’ve always got it wrong – grand-uncle or
grand-nephew – and we’ve been like this for long, always
Kashmir without Kashmiris, all for a song.</description></item><item><title>Roseburn Sleeps At Night</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/07/p747/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 06:31:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/07/p747/</guid><description>If you’re wondering who we are, let me unravel the mystery. We are the untethered children of those that live rich, tethered lives. Filled with reckless desire, unlimited ambition and thriving delusions. The unwilling bearer of it all? The place we grew up in and never grew out of – Roseburn – the perfect little island, surrounded by The City on all sides. It has everything. High-rises, row-houses, commercial blocks filled with multi-national corporations, comedy-clubs, jazz clubs, chain restaurants, local haunts, internationally recognised educational institutions, a massive hospital and a few hundred medical clinics serving the people and pets of.</description></item></channel></rss>