<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>B1 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/issue/b1/</link><description>Recent content in B1 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 06:10:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/issue/b1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deepti Kapoor – interviewed by Michelle D’Costa</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/05/p542/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 06:10:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/05/p542/</guid><description>This interview was conducted by e-mail. It is about Deepti Kapoor’s novel A Bad Character, first published by Penguin Random House, 2014.
About the novel (from Goodreads)
A highly charged fiction debut about a young woman in India, and the love that both shatters and transforms her. She is twenty, restless in New Delhi. Her mother has died; her father has left for Singapore. He is a few years older, just back to India from New York.</description></item><item><title>Two Poems – by Suhit Kelkar</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/05/p540/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 06:06:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/05/p540/</guid><description>Isosceles Majesty
It fluttered into sight,
forming ripples
on the night’s cool surface –
a faint beacon of grey,
the outlines blending.
It settled on the doorframe,
within reach of my tiny palms,
and I caught a glimpse of a plump body
tapering to a pointy end.
It would have been
merely incongruous
without the isosceles majesty
of swept-back wings –
stiff, powder-coated, frantic,
flapping in my fumbling grasp.
I grabbed the strange creature.</description></item><item><title>Beds – by Harnidh Kaur</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/04/p537/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 03:52:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/04/p537/</guid><description>Four corners of a sheet tucked in haphazardly, little island of certainty for when the floor wobbles and the roof stares down at your eyes, a game of blink with stakes too high to forfeit – empty eggshells of unmade memories, ghost limbs curved into clammy folds, piled upon each other, want braided into need, tied with a ribbon-wisp torn off cotton sheets.
This is where screams are cushioned by pillows stuffed with dreams, where babies roll off the sides with such soft grace, tumbling over warnings, where hurt is first felt, an angry, red vision that floods nights, fevered breath and salt burning cheeks as it cuts a canyon of unsaid words, tectonic plates under lips shaking and shifting till their corners tighten a little permanently.</description></item></channel></rss>