<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>B2 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/issue/b2/</link><description>Recent content in B2 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 03:42:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/issue/b2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>City Life</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/07/p583/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 03:42:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/07/p583/</guid><description>Visualise:
A bus. Of white colour, with two sky-blue stripes just below the roof and another two just above the wheels. On the white surface under the windows, Barasat to Botanical Garden is written in red, in Bengali. The road on which it is moving is not entirely smooth, and not without potholes. Therefore, while moving, it makes a certain creaking, drumming noise that is so common among buses in Kolkata.</description></item><item><title>The Girl Who Kissed Shah Rukh Khan</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/07/p577/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 01:29:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/07/p577/</guid><description>Chances are you’ve seen my girlfriend. In that tangerine spaghetti strapped shirt. Her hand cupping the stubble on Shah Rukh Khan’s chin. Her shiny straight hair hitting the sharpness of her jaw, her lips puckered and pushed out to meet his gaunt cheeks. Shah Rukh stared back at the camera, poker-fucking straight. If you looked closely enough, you’ll see her eyelashes have too much mascara on them. Clumps of hair in black goop.</description></item><item><title>Canned Life</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/07/p571/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 09:55:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/07/p571/</guid><description>We stood in front of the digital display, staring at the screen space beside the number of our flight. Our flight was delayed.
‘Yes?’ Avni asked me, nudging my hip with an elbow.
‘Yes.’
‘I knew it.’
‘No, you didn’t.’
‘I did. I knew something like this would happen.’
She glared at me. There was anger on her face. A twelve year old should not feel that the world is conspiring against her, I thought.</description></item></channel></rss>