<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dion D’Souza on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/author/dion-dsouza/</link><description>Recent content in Dion D’Souza on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 13:47:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/author/dion-dsouza/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Do I Remember Thee? – by Dion D’Souza</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/p459/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 13:47:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/p459/</guid><description>**Notes on Arun Sagar’s Anamnesia
**
Arun’s Sagar’s debut collection of poems, Anamnesia, opens with the image of a lake. At the end of the poem, the narrator, overwhelmed by ‘the ache/of vistas’ and much like the empty ‘concrete bowl’ before him, waits eagerly and with peaceful resignation—in his case, for a flood of memories and sensory impressions (‘Beginnings’). Reading through the collection, the reader becomes witness to a ‘jagged summer rain’ of diverse sights, sounds and images.</description></item><item><title>The Last Show – by Dion D’Souza</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/05/p174/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 11:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/05/p174/</guid><description>It is quite possible that I took a wrong turn as I was walking down the quiet, dark corridor, fumbling my way out of the building. There was no one behind me, though in all likelihood, that was because most of the other patrons (there had been just a handful in attendance to begin with) had chosen to take the exit to the left. I do not usually watch movies at this theatre, but it was the only one in the vicinity screening this film, and because I very much wanted to watch it, I had travelled here not entirely out of choice.</description></item></channel></rss>