<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2017 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/</link><description>Recent content in 2017 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 05:34:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Wound, Therapy &amp; Vigilance in Sophia Naz’s Poetry – by Uttaran Das Gupta</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/12/p635/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 05:34:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/12/p635/</guid><description>Very early in Sophia Naz’s _Poin_tillism we encounter the poem “Chappan Churri”, about one Janaki Bai who was stabbed fifty-six (chappan, in Urdu/Hindu) times by a jilted lover, but survived. While this is a comment on the sort of violently obsessive love glamorised in films such as Darr (1993), Raanjhanaa (2013) and others, it is also a reflection on the violence of language and memory:
When I type
churri, autocorrect is also</description></item><item><title>Two Poems – by Biswamit Dwibedy</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/12/p629/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 04:00:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/12/p629/</guid><description>To preserve formatting, the poems are available for reading in PDF.
Click Two Poems</description></item><item><title>Two Poems – by Manjiri Indurkar</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/12/p627/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 03:55:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/12/p627/</guid><description>**Diabetes at a Birthday Party
**
On a channel, a day late in celebrating
Lata Mangeshkar’s birthday,
plays a song where Sadhana promises to haunt her lover
and Ma pierces a needle in her large stomach
pushing insulin into her body
diabetes, she reminds me, will eat your bones.
if you ever look at pictures
of those suffering from rheumatoid arthritis
you will find the bones parting ways from each other.</description></item><item><title>A Sense of Leaving – by Arun Sagar</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/11/p615/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 09:37:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/11/p615/</guid><description>To preserve formatting, the poem is available for reading in PDF.
Click A Sense Of Leaving – Arun Sagar</description></item><item><title>How to Enter a Poem – by Abbas Bagasrawala</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/11/p611/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 09:32:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/11/p611/</guid><description>To preserve formatting, the poem is available for reading in PDF.
Click How To Enter A Poem</description></item><item><title>Two poems – by Nabanita Kanungo</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/08/p596/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 16:23:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/08/p596/</guid><description>SEASON
Death is a sure scent beyond the compound
and his season has arrived about a month ago.
There are no cats in the vicinity.
Only a dangerous number of young dogs.
The regular mate isn’t around.
Her owner has taken her away on a holiday.
One day, his risks at luring someone else paid off
and the ensuing rituals offered neighbours hope
that the embarrassment may stop.
But the scuffles and races must have been too brief</description></item><item><title>City Life – by Anirban Nanda</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/07/p583/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 03:42:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/07/p583/</guid><description>Visualise:
A bus. Of white colour, with two sky-blue stripes just below the roof and another two just above the wheels. On the white surface under the windows, Barasat to Botanical Garden is written in red, in Bengali. The road on which it is moving is not entirely smooth, and not without potholes. Therefore, while moving, it makes a certain creaking, drumming noise that is so common among buses in Kolkata.</description></item><item><title>The Girl Who Kissed Shah Rukh Khan – by Rheea Mukherjee</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/07/p577/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 01:29:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/07/p577/</guid><description>Chances are you’ve seen my girlfriend. In that tangerine spaghetti strapped shirt. Her hand cupping the stubble on Shah Rukh Khan’s chin. Her shiny straight hair hitting the sharpness of her jaw, her lips puckered and pushed out to meet his gaunt cheeks. Shah Rukh stared back at the camera, poker-fucking straight. If you looked closely enough, you’ll see her eyelashes have too much mascara on them. Clumps of hair in black goop.</description></item><item><title>Canned Life – by Ajay Patri</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/07/p571/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 09:55:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/07/p571/</guid><description>We stood in front of the digital display, staring at the screen space beside the number of our flight. Our flight was delayed.
‘Yes?’ Avni asked me, nudging my hip with an elbow.
‘Yes.’
‘I knew it.’
‘No, you didn’t.’
‘I did. I knew something like this would happen.’
She glared at me. There was anger on her face. A twelve year old should not feel that the world is conspiring against her, I thought.</description></item><item><title>Deepti Kapoor – interviewed by Michelle D’Costa</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/05/p542/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 06:10:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/05/p542/</guid><description>This interview was conducted by e-mail. It is about Deepti Kapoor’s novel A Bad Character, first published by Penguin Random House, 2014.
About the novel (from Goodreads)
A highly charged fiction debut about a young woman in India, and the love that both shatters and transforms her. She is twenty, restless in New Delhi. Her mother has died; her father has left for Singapore. He is a few years older, just back to India from New York.</description></item><item><title>Two Poems – by Suhit Kelkar</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/05/p540/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 06:06:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/05/p540/</guid><description>Isosceles Majesty
It fluttered into sight,
forming ripples
on the night’s cool surface –
a faint beacon of grey,
the outlines blending.
It settled on the doorframe,
within reach of my tiny palms,
and I caught a glimpse of a plump body
tapering to a pointy end.
It would have been
merely incongruous
without the isosceles majesty
of swept-back wings –
stiff, powder-coated, frantic,
flapping in my fumbling grasp.
I grabbed the strange creature.</description></item><item><title>Beds – by Harnidh Kaur</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/04/p537/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 03:52:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/04/p537/</guid><description>Four corners of a sheet tucked in haphazardly, little island of certainty for when the floor wobbles and the roof stares down at your eyes, a game of blink with stakes too high to forfeit – empty eggshells of unmade memories, ghost limbs curved into clammy folds, piled upon each other, want braided into need, tied with a ribbon-wisp torn off cotton sheets.
This is where screams are cushioned by pillows stuffed with dreams, where babies roll off the sides with such soft grace, tumbling over warnings, where hurt is first felt, an angry, red vision that floods nights, fevered breath and salt burning cheeks as it cuts a canyon of unsaid words, tectonic plates under lips shaking and shifting till their corners tighten a little permanently.</description></item></channel></rss>