<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2015 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/</link><description>Recent content in 2015 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 16:55:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Love in a Small Town</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/10/p385/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 16:55:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/10/p385/</guid><description>When Colonel Aravindan Nair took him out back to the great grounds bordering his rubber estate, Panikker assumed that it was to show him the site of the prospective wedding. He expected the Colonel to stretch his brawny arms and say, ‘A tent this big’ or stomp his foot and proclaim, ‘lunch for a thousand guests here, there a podium, and of course, changing areas! – and all this depends on you, Panikker.</description></item><item><title>With Love, Vincent</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/10/p381/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 17:35:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/10/p381/</guid><description>(A reimagining of a day in the life of Vincent van Gogh)
My dear Theo…
The moon shines with a vengeance tonight, dear brother, but no I must not worry you. Yes, it sounds lovely, and I have always loved words. The sound they make. Like wind chimes, the rustle of wheat fields, the ripple of… ripples, words, the moon looks curiously on at me as if I knew her secrets, do you remember as boys you once tore off the kitchen linen, the screeching noise it made, no not that sound no anything but that oh what have I said?</description></item><item><title>Interviewing a Beetroot</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/09/p372/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 16:00:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/09/p372/</guid><description>To preserve the format, here is the linked pdf with the poem.
Interviewing a Beetroot_TBLM</description></item><item><title>Anees Salim</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/09/p358/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 15:38:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/09/p358/</guid><description>Anees Salim is one of the most prominent and critically acclaimed novelists in India today. He has published four novels, namely The Vicks Mango Tree, Tales From A Vending Machine, Vanity Bagh, and The Blind Lady’s Descendants. Of these, Vanity Bagh won the The Hindu Literary Prize in 2013 and The Blind Lady’s Descendants won the Crossword Book Award for English Fiction 2014.
Salim’s narrators retain a straight-faced sense of humour in the face of great personal tragedy and sometimes perform the function of social commentary, the latter never out of any sense of solutionism or false idealism.</description></item><item><title>Our Bindu Didimoni</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/07/p342/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 06:33:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/07/p342/</guid><description>Bindu Didimoni, as everyone called her in our small town, had spent her life punishing high school girls. For thirty years and more, she had worked as the headmistress of Kanaklata Memorial Girls’ High School, the one and only institution of basic public education for girls in our town. Kneeling down with our hands held high in the air in the middle of the school assembly, squatting like hens with our fingers touching the lobes of our ears inside classrooms reserved for girls much younger than us, making us stand with our tongues sticking out outside the school-gate for all passersby to see; she had made us do them all.</description></item><item><title>Boundaries</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/07/p340/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 06:28:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/07/p340/</guid><description>summer garbage below
stench rises like yeast
to this fourth floor trap
I strip, circle a dot on a map
a different heat rises
the Tao says
enjoy your food, your family
your garden, your neighbor –
I hear roosters crow
in another country
I am bound to you, I said
I am bound to you, you said
cords of haste waste tangles
underlying current flowing blithe –
forgotten
wave</description></item><item><title>Jeena</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/07/p338/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 06:25:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/07/p338/</guid><description>Girl came to me in a dream and a ugly mark on her chest made me weep with beauty and look at this you see there are ways in the world where brownness of skin makes a boy (ahmed) weep because he is afraid of acknowledging his own brownness even though he listens to wiz khalifa he stands alone in the kitchen at 655pm on Wednesday evening and makes fragrant thick haleem and I think of my mom wrinkling her forehead and worrying about me and then I weep and you see how weeping becomes a circle when you weep far enough?</description></item><item><title>sketches</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/05/p325/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 14:51:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/05/p325/</guid><description>sisyphus at nizamuddin. the veiled sadness on a man’s face as he brings in one hand a bucket of dirty utensils, and in another the weight of the earth. sunlight drops on us like a curtain. the earth is spliced by a sunday. watch these men go about their lives the same way for years, the same day lived again and again for eternity.
she. began talking about her life to all and sundry.</description></item><item><title>Two Poems</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/05/p320/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 14:44:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/05/p320/</guid><description>**Hotel Lobby: Sultanahmet Istanbul
**
After the mosque and the church, some chestnuts,
after the rain— every drop a passport
to misery— we return to a room not housekept.
As we wait, we’re offered Turkish tea and Apple tea.
The family next to us is, we learn, from Germany.
Well, they’re Iraqis from Germany. We’re Indians
from America. But this evening, we’re all in the lobby
of a hotel in Sultanahmet: united against</description></item><item><title>Srinath Perur</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/05/p299/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 13:57:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/05/p299/</guid><description>We at TBLM have long felt the lack of a certain kind of conversation in the Indian literary discourse. There are interviews, yes, but these tend to be promotional in nature, and a writer generally makes appearances around a book launch. That is perhaps a necessity. But the writer interview, one that focuses on the process behind a book, its connection with the writer’s personality, her or his life before and after publication, her or his views about money, rewards and recognition in literary pursuits — is neither present nor being asked for.</description></item><item><title>An Email on Sunday</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/04/p293/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 02:04:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/04/p293/</guid><description>**An Email on Sunday
**
Some emails
are more difficult
to receive
from a child
long out of college
the daughter who writes
her cancer is back
but the doctor says
with chemo and surgery
things should be fine
and all the while
the father wonders
why she didn’t call
at midnight and let
the telephone scream
hysterically in the night
to deliver the news
a computer is too
cold a messenger</description></item><item><title>Two Poems</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/04/p291/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 02:02:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/04/p291/</guid><description>Varanasi, December 2014
You unwelcomed me with fog
on a blinding night
hurrying into history
like the feet of your ghaats
As I crawl up
the rickety slope
of your refrigerated afternoon
I am spiral and backward
in time’s forsaken bedroom
where chaste Hindi adulterates
several slips of tongues
and the languid orality of people
mulls over suicidal lungs
You rise at sundown
by the Ganges
You bathe, you shiver</description></item><item><title>A Perfect Pair of Feet</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/04/p288/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 01:58:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/04/p288/</guid><description>I watched Murenga sleep wearing a slight frown on his face, both hands tightly gripping the duvet, half of which lay on the floor on his side. He was a furnace and, even with the thermostat turned down, I felt the heat radiating from his sweat-soaked side of the bed. His legs were restless, twitching and kicking as though he was fleeing some horrible monster in his dreams. I couldn’t sleep, but I preferred this—me watching over him than him watching over me.</description></item><item><title>The Art of Flight</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/02/p275/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 15:03:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/02/p275/</guid><description>It came down to a slip of paper, an official form: A-354. If André had been a clochard, a homeless bum, it wouldn’t have mattered. Paris’ so-called free spirits, as liberated as any dog (except those they leash around), were notorious for not caring for regulation. Freezing on a slab of sidewalk in winter they’d accept a cup of soup but nothing that entailed the dreaded red tape. André wasn’t a clochard, just down at the heels, down on his luck, down but not out.</description></item><item><title>Poema</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/02/p271/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 14:48:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/02/p271/</guid><description>**I (or The End Of Life)
**
You talk sad.
I talk expensive.
Potato tart appetisers
are rare. Baby shrimp are rare.
But you dog!
It is true.
I am hungry.
Goodbye my waiter!
It is closing time.
**II (or It Is The Nature of The Weightless To Soar)
**
Inside I am blue.
You are invisible within.
For those watching
you are an elegant dinosaur
I am a blue whale</description></item><item><title>Two Poems</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/02/p269/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 14:40:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/02/p269/</guid><description>**ADDING AND SUBTRACTING
**
I always loved math, but was terrible at it. Even now, when I see cars coming towards me, it reminds me of these feelings and how I am glad I have them, and then sorry to have them, and then happy, and how there are two cars coming towards me, then three, now four, and I am fifty four, then five years old, then six, then seven, and soon eight, and there is one sun in the sky, it’s so beautiful, and then zero.</description></item><item><title>The American</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/01/p254/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:21:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/01/p254/</guid><description>_The story was first published in UpRightDown; also anthologized in Best of the Web 2009, edited by Lee K. Abbott
_
They lunch at L’olivier, and during her first glass A– says, There was a tourist. Of course there was, D– chides, her disgust for tourists as palpable as the crème brûlée she abuses with her spoon. Was he good in bed, at least? C– asks. Except for the swearing, A– says, yes.</description></item><item><title>No Town for Love</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/01/p252/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:15:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/01/p252/</guid><description>While a smooth curving flyover on the national highway cleanly bypassed the town of Moradabad, if one had to go there, it had to be with purpose. The unending markets on either side of the congested roads screamed with the clamor of commerce. Motor workshops jostled easily with shops processing grain and pulses, gur and khandsari . Ancient eateries frying jalebis and kachauris vied to generate more heat and smell than the myriad brass metal units outflanking them.</description></item><item><title>Keeping Pace</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/01/p249/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:10:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/01/p249/</guid><description>I was the first woman in his life, she, the most recent. Apart from him, the other thing we had in common was running. I’d finished one full and three half marathons. She was attempting her first 10k. The type of distance that becomes an accessory. She was the type of artist that makes a living out of being one. Her 10k goal was an urban layer of achievement that adds nicely to a personality.</description></item></channel></rss>