<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fiction on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/category/fiction/</link><description>Recent content in fiction on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 03:11:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/category/fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>चेरी ब्लॉसम</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2019/09/p908/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 03:11:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2019/09/p908/</guid><description>उसने अपने कोट के बटन कंठ तक बंद किए और हथेलियाँ रगड़कर गालों पर लगाई। हज़ारों मील और दो मौसमों की दूरी कुछ घंटों में पार, धरती छोड़ी तो मुम्बई का समुद्री पवन और उतरो तो टोक्यो की हिमानी हवा।
“टोक्यो के वसंत में आपका स्वागत है”, उतरने से पहले पॉयलट ने घोषणा की थी, “आप भाग्यशाली हैं कि चेरी ब्लॉसम वाले सप्ताहांत में आप इस खूबसूरत शहर में हैं। डाउन टाउन गिंजा की साकूरा डोरी, हिबिया पार्क, इम्पीरियल पैलेस के आस-पास और टोक्यो के सभी उपनगरों में चेरी के श्वेत गुलाबी फूल खिल रहे हैं।”</description></item><item><title>On Lighting Up</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/12/p520/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 14:54:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/12/p520/</guid><description>That day, we watched Patchaikili Muthucharam, studying the contours of Sarathkumar’s triceps, while he exclaimed all the while semma body I’m telling you it’s aatukaal soup with extra blood. I had no frame of reference; the only blood I sought was sparse every month and irrevocably stained the satin underwear I bought at the export store in Pondicherry. When I had gone to buy them, the saleswomen giggled uncontrollably and adjusted their dupattas when I told them to let him into the trial room.</description></item><item><title>Silence</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/p470/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 04:20:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/p470/</guid><description>You cannot believe it is time for her to leave. Fifteen years. Really?
You were only ten when she started working for your family, probably her first expat family. She had worked for local families before yours, you know. She seemed like every other nanny your parents had hired, when she worked only part-time. Only later did you start appreciating her, when she lived with you.
You have been in the company of nannies much longer than you have been with your parents, so you know you can differentiate between the good ones and the bad ones.</description></item><item><title>The Faraway Things</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/07/p192/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 12:25:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/07/p192/</guid><description>A Piki Tup garbage van rattles past Kero as she winces at the four-inch face of her phone. The familiar odour of rotting trash wafts into her nostrils. She frowns, looks up, curbs an urge to spit, then down again. She quickly finds her place in the text message she is re-reading. It confounds her even more. She wishes the bus would come already. With the exception of the one time she had missed it, the five o’clock bus to Highlands North had never been on time.</description></item><item><title>The Balance in Silence</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/07/p189/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 04:25:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/07/p189/</guid><description>I watch the tide of a new morning in the pallor of the curtains against the pane of the bedroom window. Except for the birds on the mango tree outside and an occasional vehicle that honks on the stray dogs, there is no sound.
Nothing has changed while we slept.
A morning person, I look with disappointment at Tina, the wife I once loved. The wife I am trying to love again.</description></item></channel></rss>