<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fiction on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/category/fiction/</link><description>Recent content in fiction on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 03:11:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/category/fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>चेरी ब्लॉसम</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2019/09/p908/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 03:11:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2019/09/p908/</guid><description>उसने अपने कोट के बटन कंठ तक बंद किए और हथेलियाँ रगड़कर गालों पर लगाई। हज़ारों मील और दो मौसमों की दूरी कुछ घंटों में पार, धरती छोड़ी तो मुम्बई का समुद्री पवन और उतरो तो टोक्यो की हिमानी हवा।
“टोक्यो के वसंत में आपका स्वागत है”, उतरने से पहले पॉयलट ने घोषणा की थी, “आप भाग्यशाली हैं कि चेरी ब्लॉसम वाले सप्ताहांत में आप इस खूबसूरत शहर में हैं। डाउन टाउन गिंजा की साकूरा डोरी, हिबिया पार्क, इम्पीरियल पैलेस के आस-पास और टोक्यो के सभी उपनगरों में चेरी के श्वेत गुलाबी फूल खिल रहे हैं।”</description></item><item><title>On Lighting Up</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/12/p520/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 14:54:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/12/p520/</guid><description>That day, we watched Patchaikili Muthucharam, studying the contours of Sarathkumar’s triceps, while he exclaimed all the while semma body I’m telling you it’s aatukaal soup with extra blood. I had no frame of reference; the only blood I sought was sparse every month and irrevocably stained the satin underwear I bought at the export store in Pondicherry. When I had gone to buy them, the saleswomen giggled uncontrollably and adjusted their dupattas when I told them to let him into the trial room.</description></item><item><title>Silence</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/p470/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 04:20:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/p470/</guid><description>You cannot believe it is time for her to leave. Fifteen years. Really?
You were only ten when she started working for your family, probably her first expat family. She had worked for local families before yours, you know. She seemed like every other nanny your parents had hired, when she worked only part-time. Only later did you start appreciating her, when she lived with you.
You have been in the company of nannies much longer than you have been with your parents, so you know you can differentiate between the good ones and the bad ones.</description></item><item><title>Jeena</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/07/p338/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 06:25:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/07/p338/</guid><description>Girl came to me in a dream and a ugly mark on her chest made me weep with beauty and look at this you see there are ways in the world where brownness of skin makes a boy (ahmed) weep because he is afraid of acknowledging his own brownness even though he listens to wiz khalifa he stands alone in the kitchen at 655pm on Wednesday evening and makes fragrant thick haleem and I think of my mom wrinkling her forehead and worrying about me and then I weep and you see how weeping becomes a circle when you weep far enough?</description></item><item><title>A Perfect Pair of Feet</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/04/p288/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 01:58:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/04/p288/</guid><description>I watched Murenga sleep wearing a slight frown on his face, both hands tightly gripping the duvet, half of which lay on the floor on his side. He was a furnace and, even with the thermostat turned down, I felt the heat radiating from his sweat-soaked side of the bed. His legs were restless, twitching and kicking as though he was fleeing some horrible monster in his dreams. I couldn’t sleep, but I preferred this—me watching over him than him watching over me.</description></item><item><title>The Art of Flight</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/02/p275/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 15:03:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/02/p275/</guid><description>It came down to a slip of paper, an official form: A-354. If André had been a clochard, a homeless bum, it wouldn’t have mattered. Paris’ so-called free spirits, as liberated as any dog (except those they leash around), were notorious for not caring for regulation. Freezing on a slab of sidewalk in winter they’d accept a cup of soup but nothing that entailed the dreaded red tape. André wasn’t a clochard, just down at the heels, down on his luck, down but not out.</description></item><item><title>The American</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/01/p254/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:21:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/01/p254/</guid><description>_The story was first published in UpRightDown; also anthologized in Best of the Web 2009, edited by Lee K. Abbott
_
They lunch at L’olivier, and during her first glass A– says, There was a tourist. Of course there was, D– chides, her disgust for tourists as palpable as the crème brûlée she abuses with her spoon. Was he good in bed, at least? C– asks. Except for the swearing, A– says, yes.</description></item><item><title>No Town for Love</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/01/p252/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:15:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/01/p252/</guid><description>While a smooth curving flyover on the national highway cleanly bypassed the town of Moradabad, if one had to go there, it had to be with purpose. The unending markets on either side of the congested roads screamed with the clamor of commerce. Motor workshops jostled easily with shops processing grain and pulses, gur and khandsari . Ancient eateries frying jalebis and kachauris vied to generate more heat and smell than the myriad brass metal units outflanking them.</description></item><item><title>Keeping Pace</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/01/p249/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:10:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/01/p249/</guid><description>I was the first woman in his life, she, the most recent. Apart from him, the other thing we had in common was running. I’d finished one full and three half marathons. She was attempting her first 10k. The type of distance that becomes an accessory. She was the type of artist that makes a living out of being one. Her 10k goal was an urban layer of achievement that adds nicely to a personality.</description></item><item><title>Because If Nothing Matters</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/12/p225/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 13:43:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/12/p225/</guid><description>It didn’t occur to me till much later that Joe had stopped coming to the library. I used to go to the British Council library regularly, and had chatted with him a couple of times. Now I had often met curious people before but he was the most eccentric among the lot. The kind that spend whole afternoons amidst stacks not because they like being surrounded by books, but because they have nowhere else to go.</description></item><item><title>Hope That He Hears</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/12/p221/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 16:39:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/12/p221/</guid><description>You are secretly in love with your cousin. Every vacation, in your grandmother’s house, you watch him grow a few more inches, and of late display a few more sprouts of hair. You marvel at how his voice is better than that of any boy you have heard. You also marvel at how he can sing English songs you have never heard before. Every time he touches your palm, in an attempt to teach you the right way to strike on the carrom board, you struggle to control your smile, and struggle to control the spreading of a warm, fuzzy feeling that honestly leaves you baffled.</description></item><item><title>The Tourist</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/10/p213/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 04:53:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/10/p213/</guid><description>The line outside the lunch hall was far too long- out of the weather worn tarpaulin it went, curving at oblique points of chatter and conversation, scattering into a thicket of small and smaller children, and finally into a throng of ladies all clad in starched shades of gold, green or red; men were scant, the few around the marriage hall could be seen walking about nestling half empty bottles of aquafina or nippled bottles of pale warm milk.</description></item><item><title>Fault</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/08/p208/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 12:43:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/08/p208/</guid><description>During the days we met, the rains were light. The mushrooms behind the house had weeded brown and you had said how sitting by them I looked like the boy who came out of water in a certain book you had read recently. On Fridays, you came early with a polythene packet knit gently around your wrist, dangling.
“Baruahs sold out for the day. Just the last two. Lucky! Aren’t we?</description></item><item><title>Hobby</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/08/p198/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 18:04:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/08/p198/</guid><description>What Girish knew about having sex with a woman came from spending hours studying his grandfather, the old watchmaker, repair old clocks.
Around the time that Girish turned 16, he found that the process of mending something broken and allowing something to chime again fascinated him more than even cricket. There was something soothing about his grandfather’s painstaking ways of repairing watches and clocks. He decided to study how his grandfather repaired time pieces and the study soon turned into a hobby.</description></item><item><title>The Faraway Things</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/07/p192/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 12:25:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/07/p192/</guid><description>A Piki Tup garbage van rattles past Kero as she winces at the four-inch face of her phone. The familiar odour of rotting trash wafts into her nostrils. She frowns, looks up, curbs an urge to spit, then down again. She quickly finds her place in the text message she is re-reading. It confounds her even more. She wishes the bus would come already. With the exception of the one time she had missed it, the five o’clock bus to Highlands North had never been on time.</description></item><item><title>The Balance in Silence</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/07/p189/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 04:25:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/07/p189/</guid><description>I watch the tide of a new morning in the pallor of the curtains against the pane of the bedroom window. Except for the birds on the mango tree outside and an occasional vehicle that honks on the stray dogs, there is no sound.
Nothing has changed while we slept.
A morning person, I look with disappointment at Tina, the wife I once loved. The wife I am trying to love again.</description></item><item><title>The Last Show</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/05/p174/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 11:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/05/p174/</guid><description>It is quite possible that I took a wrong turn as I was walking down the quiet, dark corridor, fumbling my way out of the building. There was no one behind me, though in all likelihood, that was because most of the other patrons (there had been just a handful in attendance to begin with) had chosen to take the exit to the left. I do not usually watch movies at this theatre, but it was the only one in the vicinity screening this film, and because I very much wanted to watch it, I had travelled here not entirely out of choice.</description></item><item><title>The Help</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/04/p166/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 14:40:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/04/p166/</guid><description>She aroused interest in Bradley like a sealed envelope could do.
He was dumb but not deaf and she did not know that.
When she realised he was dumb she assumed that he had to be deaf too.
She was the help but she was not hired to look after him.
Little did she know that to him the sounds of her washing the dishes were a melody of their own.</description></item><item><title>An Amorphous Voyage of Fleeting Seeds</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/01/p152/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 12:53:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/01/p152/</guid><description>Life came to us at that cusp of infinite void, the edge of the sun’s reach. It was a sudden awakening, though awakening might mean that we had been sleeping, been alive. We were never alive, both Kreetin and I.
Till the time our star-hopping vessel passed the heliosphere at the edge of solar system, we existed in not a deep slumber, but as lifeless crud. The understanding of all of humanity flashed onto us in a blinding instant, a drip bang boom of knowledge quicker than an antsy sneeze.</description></item><item><title>The Mummy’s Bitter And Melancholy Exile</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/01/p129/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 07:29:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/01/p129/</guid><description>_The story was first published in Cranky Literary Journal, and subsequently appeared in Lock’s newest short story collection, Love Among the Particles, published in May, 2013, by Bellevue Literary Press, New York City.
_
_Osiris, God of the Dead
_
The Mummy is invited to speak on the radio. He is driven from his apartment house through the autumn streets, toward the broadcasting studio. He looks through the limousine window at the street-cleaners sweeping the fallen leaves.</description></item><item><title>The Absentee</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/12/p122/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 11:44:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/12/p122/</guid><description>Gauri sat nervously in the lobby of a high end salon, clutching the bridal package voucher that her mother had sent her with. A few minutes later, the receptionist let her know that the beautician was ready. Eyebrows would be dealt with first. The beautician held the ends of the thread in her mouth and hands, forming like intent scissors. Tears rolled down Gauri’s cheeks as her skin smarted and cooled her warm flushed cheeks.</description></item><item><title>Preexisting Conditions</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/10/p110/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 16:50:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/10/p110/</guid><description>“Are you ready to go?” Kristine asks, unballing a pair of her pantyhose. Jack shakes his dreadlocked head and scrabbles around in the ashtray. He comes up with a nug of weed between his fingers. He carries it like a saint’s toenail over to the table, to the improvised bong. Last night, after they fought, he sawed off a pop bottle and smoked too much.
“Give me some,” Kristine says, as he takes a rattling pull.</description></item><item><title>Exile</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/09/p93/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 05:59:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/09/p93/</guid><description>Exile was first published in Issue 17 of &amp;gt;kill author.
**For my namesake
**
El desterrado es ese tipo de persona que ha perdido a su amante y busca en cada rostro nuevo el rostro querido y, siempre autoengañándose, piensa que lo ha encontrado.
The exile is the type of person who, having lost the Beloved, keeps searching for the face he loves in every new face and, forever deceiving himself, thinks he has found it.</description></item><item><title>Gasoline</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/09/p87/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 05:54:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/09/p87/</guid><description>My TV, computer and spare cash left with Laura. She’d visited her favorite shoe store with my Visa and used the back of the receipt to write a Dear Jude note. Her handwriting was precise. It explained that she would be moving to Arkansas to live with Gustav, some guy she met online, and would never be back. Looking at the receipt, I wondered if the two of them planned to open a store with all the shoes six-hundred dollars had bought.</description></item><item><title>Dream of the Butterfly</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/08/p78/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2013 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/08/p78/</guid><description>I am writing this. I want to keep writing something. I had started with something, thought of reaching somewhere. The tea is over, and it has managed to leave behind its stench in my breath. Cold is getting worse as evening is approaching…
I can’t write anymore. Few words here and there and I start getting disoriented.
So I look at her again. She is simple, there’s no applied glitter, but she radiates the magic of bygone days.</description></item><item><title>Transit for Beginners</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/08/p63/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 10:15:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/08/p63/</guid><description>I met him at Changi airport. After a seven hour flight from Tokyo, preceded by an eleven hour flight to Tokyo. My breath was stale and my deodorant had long since given up. Changi was a festival, packed with dazzling places to shop at and strange luxurious things to do. Showers with towel service, a spa, a movie theater, a twenty-four hour gym, and even a swimming pool in case the urge to swim struck while you were in between flights.</description></item><item><title>Amy and the Question of Before</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/07/p28/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 19:03:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/07/p28/</guid><description>_What do you do before you do?
_
This is a zen koan. I invented it. I was masturbating or was about to masturbate when I invented it. Actually, it is preposterously wrong to say I invented it. Nobody invents a koan, it just pops into your head. For more than an hour I grappled with mine, forgetting my sleepy dick, until I fell off the bed laughing so hard, so bodily, that all that was in my head got sucked up and dumped into my solar plexus like a sock into the pit of a heavy vacuum cleaner.</description></item><item><title>This Place can be Beautiful Again</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/06/p20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 09:53:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/06/p20/</guid><description>I sat by the river, on a damp log half-buried in mud, and watched how the yellow finger of water wound its way through the city, past gutters and factories and underneath bridges, and it smelled like the worst thing in the world. Whenever I read a poem or whatever about rivers, it’s always about the beauty and majesty of nature. I bet those writers never saw a river like this one.</description></item><item><title>Singapore Girl</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/06/p18/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 09:52:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/06/p18/</guid><description>(From Nabina Das’ soon-to-come short story collection “The House of Twining Roses – Stories of the Mapped and the Unmapped”, LiFi Publications)
When Sita stole those clothes, she was sure the old woman wouldn’t know. It was a whim anyway. Sita always did things out of whims. I’m not that type. Rather, the supportive kind. Besides, I didn’t see myself as a thief. I just gave her company. We were friends.</description></item><item><title>Mother</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/06/p15/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 09:41:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/06/p15/</guid><description>Her absence is the kitchen’s lack of aroma. Back in the day, what seemed to bind their lives from one day to the next was the sweet spicy smell that wafted from the kitchen every morning. There was something inexplicable about it. Spreading from one room to another, it used to fill their home with a sort of life-affirmation. It gave them an unconscious hope that someone was there. That someone had already greeted dawn before they broke their slumber.</description></item></channel></rss>