<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2016/06 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/</link><description>Recent content in 2016/06 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Silence</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/p470/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 04:20:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/p470/</guid><description>You cannot believe it is time for her to leave. Fifteen years. Really?
You were only ten when she started working for your family, probably her first expat family. She had worked for local families before yours, you know. She seemed like every other nanny your parents had hired, when she worked only part-time. Only later did you start appreciating her, when she lived with you.
You have been in the company of nannies much longer than you have been with your parents, so you know you can differentiate between the good ones and the bad ones.</description></item><item><title>Two poems</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/p466/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 00:10:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/p466/</guid><description>**Sally on Tambourine
**
I taught Sally how to hit her tambourine on 2 and 4. So many pink people hit on 1 and 3. And she could sing like birds: like nightingale, like whippoorwill, like western meadowlark, her voice so pure, like dawn-light, like twilight, like golden vegas, streams of light, golden fingers from the clouds. She sang for God; she sang for the group. Our praise band met Thursday nights up near the altar at the church.</description></item><item><title>How Do I Remember Thee?</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/p459/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 13:47:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/p459/</guid><description>**Notes on Arun Sagar’s Anamnesia
**
Arun’s Sagar’s debut collection of poems, Anamnesia, opens with the image of a lake. At the end of the poem, the narrator, overwhelmed by ‘the ache/of vistas’ and much like the empty ‘concrete bowl’ before him, waits eagerly and with peaceful resignation—in his case, for a flood of memories and sensory impressions (‘Beginnings’). Reading through the collection, the reader becomes witness to a ‘jagged summer rain’ of diverse sights, sounds and images.</description></item></channel></rss>