<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>B5 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/issue/b5/</link><description>Recent content in B5 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 02:57:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/issue/b5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Crow Named Black</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/01/p658/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 02:57:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/01/p658/</guid><description>Aww! Sweet! That’s my boy. Kill. Kill. Kill…No, no, no… it’s pecking his eyes out… Yess! Grabbed it by the neck. Now one snap and the head’s off, rainbow neck and plumage an’ all. I think it’s time to land on the nearest branch. A few of my brothers might be on the lookout too. Best be the first off the block! I dip down, circling the topmost branches, looking for a sturdier lower branch to land on while keeping one wary eye on the prey, or, to be honest, on the severed head of the prey which the dog has very obligingly thrown aside while starting on the body.</description></item><item><title>On Language</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/01/p650/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 02:47:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/01/p650/</guid><description>To play a sound recording of the poem (recommended), click here.
Over a cup of chaha,
I stumbled over words
through a conversation
in a Marathi influenced by the American tongue.
My relatives and friends listened
their faces falling
and at that moment
in that conversation
the distance between us was much
further than that of the Atlantic Ocean.
I’ve picked up languages until now
as a consequence of picking up my life and placing it in lands where</description></item><item><title>Call From Kyoto</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/01/p648/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 02:44:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/01/p648/</guid><description>When the phone doesn’t stop ringing,
I excuse myself from the meeting room;
watch the rain create a rhythm that fails
to touch me beyond the sound-proof glass
I have collected two seasons
since the last time you called
the tremble in your voice seeks familiarity
Konnichiwa you say in an uneasy whisper
language has abandoned your fingertips, alienated you,
your poems now merely mirror the mirage of colors, of shoes and booths,</description></item></channel></rss>