<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>reviews on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/category/reviews/</link><description>Recent content in reviews on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 11:43:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/category/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Review of Mihir Vatsa’s WINGMAN – by Medha Singh</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/05/p723/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 11:43:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/05/p723/</guid><description>Recently, a combined bundle of chapbooks by Mihir Vatsa, Nandini Dhar, Usha Akella, Manjiri Indurkar and Arjun Rajendran were released through Vayavya and Aainanagar at an event ‘Reading Five: An Evening of Poetry’ at Moti Lal Nehru college. It was a refreshing visit, that took me back to my college days when we, as English students, sat wide eyed, aware of the privilege of having an author read their work to us.</description></item><item><title>Wound, Therapy &amp; Vigilance in Sophia Naz’s Poetry – by Uttaran Das Gupta</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/12/p635/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 05:34:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/12/p635/</guid><description>Very early in Sophia Naz’s _Poin_tillism we encounter the poem “Chappan Churri”, about one Janaki Bai who was stabbed fifty-six (chappan, in Urdu/Hindu) times by a jilted lover, but survived. While this is a comment on the sort of violently obsessive love glamorised in films such as Darr (1993), Raanjhanaa (2013) and others, it is also a reflection on the violence of language and memory:
When I type
churri, autocorrect is also</description></item><item><title>How Do I Remember Thee? – by Dion D’Souza</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/p459/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 13:47:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/p459/</guid><description>**Notes on Arun Sagar’s Anamnesia
**
Arun’s Sagar’s debut collection of poems, Anamnesia, opens with the image of a lake. At the end of the poem, the narrator, overwhelmed by ‘the ache/of vistas’ and much like the empty ‘concrete bowl’ before him, waits eagerly and with peaceful resignation—in his case, for a flood of memories and sensory impressions (‘Beginnings’). Reading through the collection, the reader becomes witness to a ‘jagged summer rain’ of diverse sights, sounds and images.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Mohit Parikh’s ‘Manan’ – by Mihir Vatsa</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/12/p227/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 15:18:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/12/p227/</guid><description>Manan
by Mohit Parikh
Harper, 2014
Rs. 199
A Review
Mihir Vatsa
To Start With,
He closes his eyes and finds today’s date floating towards him. Shimmering in the darkness, swiveling— like the text on the Windows 95 screensaver. It seeps in through his forehead and gets absorbed. 23-04-98 is now a part of him. Today’s date, a Saturday, when the first sign of what he so eagerly awaited has appeared.</description></item><item><title>The Infinite Capacity for Illusion – by Riku Sayuj</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/03/p162/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 20:28:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/03/p162/</guid><description>Whither The Magic?
One Hundred Years of Solitude is one of my favorite novels. Which is why, when I started reading Love in the Time of Cholera, one of the things I noticed immediately was the lack of that subtle brand of magic that I had so enjoyed. I wanted it badly and went around every corner with the expectation of a cheerful reunion. But it was not to be.</description></item></channel></rss>