<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>4 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/issue/4/</link><description>Recent content in 4 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 12:53:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/issue/4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>An Amorphous Voyage of Fleeting Seeds</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/01/p152/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 12:53:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/01/p152/</guid><description>Life came to us at that cusp of infinite void, the edge of the sun’s reach. It was a sudden awakening, though awakening might mean that we had been sleeping, been alive. We were never alive, both Kreetin and I.
Till the time our star-hopping vessel passed the heliosphere at the edge of solar system, we existed in not a deep slumber, but as lifeless crud. The understanding of all of humanity flashed onto us in a blinding instant, a drip bang boom of knowledge quicker than an antsy sneeze.</description></item><item><title>The Mummy’s Bitter And Melancholy Exile</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/01/p129/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 07:29:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/01/p129/</guid><description>_The story was first published in Cranky Literary Journal, and subsequently appeared in Lock’s newest short story collection, Love Among the Particles, published in May, 2013, by Bellevue Literary Press, New York City.
_
_Osiris, God of the Dead
_
The Mummy is invited to speak on the radio. He is driven from his apartment house through the autumn streets, toward the broadcasting studio. He looks through the limousine window at the street-cleaners sweeping the fallen leaves.</description></item><item><title>The Absentee</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/12/p122/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 11:44:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/12/p122/</guid><description>Gauri sat nervously in the lobby of a high end salon, clutching the bridal package voucher that her mother had sent her with. A few minutes later, the receptionist let her know that the beautician was ready. Eyebrows would be dealt with first. The beautician held the ends of the thread in her mouth and hands, forming like intent scissors. Tears rolled down Gauri’s cheeks as her skin smarted and cooled her warm flushed cheeks.</description></item></channel></rss>