<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>7 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/issue/7/</link><description>Recent content in 7 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 04:53:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/issue/7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Tourist</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/10/p213/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 04:53:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/10/p213/</guid><description>The line outside the lunch hall was far too long- out of the weather worn tarpaulin it went, curving at oblique points of chatter and conversation, scattering into a thicket of small and smaller children, and finally into a throng of ladies all clad in starched shades of gold, green or red; men were scant, the few around the marriage hall could be seen walking about nestling half empty bottles of aquafina or nippled bottles of pale warm milk.</description></item><item><title>Fault</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/08/p208/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 12:43:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/08/p208/</guid><description>During the days we met, the rains were light. The mushrooms behind the house had weeded brown and you had said how sitting by them I looked like the boy who came out of water in a certain book you had read recently. On Fridays, you came early with a polythene packet knit gently around your wrist, dangling.
“Baruahs sold out for the day. Just the last two. Lucky! Aren’t we?</description></item><item><title>Hobby</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/08/p198/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 18:04:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/08/p198/</guid><description>What Girish knew about having sex with a woman came from spending hours studying his grandfather, the old watchmaker, repair old clocks.
Around the time that Girish turned 16, he found that the process of mending something broken and allowing something to chime again fascinated him more than even cricket. There was something soothing about his grandfather’s painstaking ways of repairing watches and clocks. He decided to study how his grandfather repaired time pieces and the study soon turned into a hobby.</description></item></channel></rss>