<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>C9 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/issue/c9/</link><description>Recent content in C9 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 04:22:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/issue/c9/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On Nightmares</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2019/09/p916/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 04:22:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2019/09/p916/</guid><description>Night breaks apart like pomegranate seeds in my
palm.
The juice is everywhere, but who can see things when
they spill?
There’s only the smell and the incense of the heart
vomiting into the night. The night has been cut short,
the dream severed.
The dream like an octopus chewing the naked sense
of being.
What strangeness that myth and reality come like
twins?
As long as the juice burns the hand, its exotic smell</description></item><item><title>चेरी ब्लॉसम</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2019/09/p908/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 03:11:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2019/09/p908/</guid><description>उसने अपने कोट के बटन कंठ तक बंद किए और हथेलियाँ रगड़कर गालों पर लगाई। हज़ारों मील और दो मौसमों की दूरी कुछ घंटों में पार, धरती छोड़ी तो मुम्बई का समुद्री पवन और उतरो तो टोक्यो की हिमानी हवा।
“टोक्यो के वसंत में आपका स्वागत है”, उतरने से पहले पॉयलट ने घोषणा की थी, “आप भाग्यशाली हैं कि चेरी ब्लॉसम वाले सप्ताहांत में आप इस खूबसूरत शहर में हैं। डाउन टाउन गिंजा की साकूरा डोरी, हिबिया पार्क, इम्पीरियल पैलेस के आस-पास और टोक्यो के सभी उपनगरों में चेरी के श्वेत गुलाबी फूल खिल रहे हैं।”</description></item><item><title>Your Side Of The Bed</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2019/09/p905/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 02:50:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2019/09/p905/</guid><description>Yesterday, I watched Ana buy eggs at the chicken shop down the road from our house, and just as I registered the familiar smell of her hair – mint and cucumber, washed thrice a week, always with cold water – I felt her words settle into the bends of my ear canals and say, exactly as she’d done the first time we met, You know, you can tell a good egg from the bad ones if it sinks in a mug of water.</description></item></channel></rss>