<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2018/02 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/02/</link><description>Recent content in 2018/02 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sharanya Manivannan</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/02/p687/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 17:37:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/02/p687/</guid><description>We first interviewed Sharanya Manivannan after the publication of her short story collection, The High Priestess Never Marries_. That interview can be read here. This interview was done in the light of her recent poetry collection,_ The Altar of the Only World.
**The world ‘Only’ in your title: should we pause on it? Sita, Inanna, Sita-Inanna – they reach the underworld in your poems. Yet this underworld is not the world being referred to as the only world, and is certainly not the world where the feast (let’s say the one in the poem ‘Benediction for the Feast’) eventually takes place.</description></item><item><title>At the Cafés of Your Memory</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/02/p676/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 13:37:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/02/p676/</guid><description>Faiz, what befell the fellow travelers of late last night?
Where did the morning breeze halt?
Where did morning alight?
Faiz Ahmed Faiz
At an avant-garde café in uptown Pune,
the reserved tables celebrate
a teenager’s birthday in cosmopolitan English.
My nearly dead phone flares up with a call from home:
My mother laments in frayed Kashmiri:
_I am happy you aren’t home, two boys
were shot dead today.</description></item><item><title>//a mug hung around their necks like the curse of Ashwaththama//</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/02/p673/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 13:32:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/02/p673/</guid><description>An overturned anda-bhurji cart of a hawker during a riot.
She who had borrowed money to set up this stall
brought in twelve crates of eggs for the day,
freshly baked loafs of bread, 5 kilo onions wholesale
and few cheap refined-oil cans by selling
all the clothes she owns
except the sari that she now adorns.
Stocks of beedis lying on the ground;
awaiting whores
for you to take a drag from your filthy mouths,</description></item><item><title>The Birth</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/02/p670/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 13:24:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/02/p670/</guid><description>It was February when we wheeled my sister into the hospital, her eyes shut close with pain. There was always someone touching her hair, her hand, always someone telling her that it would be alright, everything would be fine, but also sobbing as they said it, while she drifted in and out of consciousness. The hospital was quiet, the nurses talked quietly. People waiting outside the ICU wore sweaters and caps in bright colors.</description></item></channel></rss>