<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Medha Singh on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/author/medha-singh/</link><description>Recent content in Medha Singh on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 02:29:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/author/medha-singh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Three Poems – by Medha Singh</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2020/05/p1057/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 02:29:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2020/05/p1057/</guid><description>I Hear Father is Dead in Another Country
One is as old as the days they remember.
Some make us age quicker, better.
Some slow in pace: something between a wish
and a prayer, something
that is both. Some call it hope. It’s not.
Light sweeping the white sand, across
the cool and quiet sea. Here, his consoling hand
on my face; fast arriving, a withered brow,
reaching, touching,
brown, low.</description></item><item><title>Review of Mihir Vatsa’s WINGMAN – by Medha Singh</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/05/p723/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 11:43:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/05/p723/</guid><description>Recently, a combined bundle of chapbooks by Mihir Vatsa, Nandini Dhar, Usha Akella, Manjiri Indurkar and Arjun Rajendran were released through Vayavya and Aainanagar at an event ‘Reading Five: An Evening of Poetry’ at Moti Lal Nehru college. It was a refreshing visit, that took me back to my college days when we, as English students, sat wide eyed, aware of the privilege of having an author read their work to us.</description></item><item><title>sketches – by Medha Singh</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/05/p325/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 14:51:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/05/p325/</guid><description>sisyphus at nizamuddin. the veiled sadness on a man’s face as he brings in one hand a bucket of dirty utensils, and in another the weight of the earth. sunlight drops on us like a curtain. the earth is spliced by a sunday. watch these men go about their lives the same way for years, the same day lived again and again for eternity.
she. began talking about her life to all and sundry.</description></item></channel></rss>