<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2016 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/</link><description>Recent content in 2016 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 07:20:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Two Poems – by Mihir Chitre</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/12/p528/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 07:20:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/12/p528/</guid><description>Study Leave
There is one tubelight in the hall
and the windows, whose glasses
are either broken or sold off,
give away more than they should.
I am studying the adjective clause
but can’t find one to describe my father.
What is it that he will blame my mother for tonight
before thrashing her against the wall?
I taper through the scissors of possibilities.
A private fear frosts my mind.</description></item><item><title>Sharanya Manivannan – interviewed by Tanuj Solanki</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/12/p522/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 15:42:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/12/p522/</guid><description>Barring a couple of stories, the protagonists in your stories can be said to be in stasis. They end where they begin; or if there is a change, it serves only to make them more conscious of their conflicts, paradoxes. Thought of from a technical viewpoint, stasis is the enemy of plot. What are your views on this thing called plot? How comfortable are you with it, and will we ever see you write a traditionally—for want of a better word—plotted work?</description></item><item><title>On Lighting Up – by Ranjani Murali</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/12/p520/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 14:54:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/12/p520/</guid><description>That day, we watched Patchaikili Muthucharam, studying the contours of Sarathkumar’s triceps, while he exclaimed all the while semma body I’m telling you it’s aatukaal soup with extra blood. I had no frame of reference; the only blood I sought was sparse every month and irrevocably stained the satin underwear I bought at the export store in Pondicherry. When I had gone to buy them, the saleswomen giggled uncontrollably and adjusted their dupattas when I told them to let him into the trial room.</description></item><item><title>Nallamma – by Iniyavan Banumathi</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/08/p504/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/08/p504/</guid><description>To preserve the format, we’ve made Nallamma available on this link</description></item><item><title>Beloved K – by Aditi Uniyal</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/08/p497/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 11:44:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/08/p497/</guid><description>I have dug knives in your shoulders
carefully, and they are still trying to
go deeper into your warm flesh-
I am sorry, dear, but I don’t know if
I can remove all of them without
spilling any more blood than what
already runs off the valleys of your back.
I have shot at your belly so you
can never bear any children,
and bullets are all you can digest now-</description></item><item><title>The Biggest Enemy of Rain – by Manu Bhattathiri</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/08/p494/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 11:40:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/08/p494/</guid><description>Contrary to popular belief, the biggest enemy of rain is not the rapid felling of trees. Nor is it rising global temperatures, industrialization, the burning of fossil fuels or even that telltale hole in the sky. The single biggest enemy of rain is a person by the name of Gopi and he still lives in our little town and he still hates rain.
We would sit on a parapet by a small creek, a group of us younger old men and Gopi, who was old enough to be reborn a toddler.</description></item><item><title>Silence – By Michelle D’Costa</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/p470/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 04:20:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/p470/</guid><description>You cannot believe it is time for her to leave. Fifteen years. Really?
You were only ten when she started working for your family, probably her first expat family. She had worked for local families before yours, you know. She seemed like every other nanny your parents had hired, when she worked only part-time. Only later did you start appreciating her, when she lived with you.
You have been in the company of nannies much longer than you have been with your parents, so you know you can differentiate between the good ones and the bad ones.</description></item><item><title>Two poems – by Kevin Rabas</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/p466/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 00:10:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/p466/</guid><description>**Sally on Tambourine
**
I taught Sally how to hit her tambourine on 2 and 4. So many pink people hit on 1 and 3. And she could sing like birds: like nightingale, like whippoorwill, like western meadowlark, her voice so pure, like dawn-light, like twilight, like golden vegas, streams of light, golden fingers from the clouds. She sang for God; she sang for the group. Our praise band met Thursday nights up near the altar at the church.</description></item><item><title>How Do I Remember Thee? – by Dion D’Souza</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/p459/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 13:47:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/06/p459/</guid><description>**Notes on Arun Sagar’s Anamnesia
**
Arun’s Sagar’s debut collection of poems, Anamnesia, opens with the image of a lake. At the end of the poem, the narrator, overwhelmed by ‘the ache/of vistas’ and much like the empty ‘concrete bowl’ before him, waits eagerly and with peaceful resignation—in his case, for a flood of memories and sensory impressions (‘Beginnings’). Reading through the collection, the reader becomes witness to a ‘jagged summer rain’ of diverse sights, sounds and images.</description></item><item><title>Rheea Mukherjee — interviewed by TBLM Staff</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/03/p434/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 08:27:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/03/p434/</guid><description>**First of all, let me congratulate you on compiling a collection of short stories. It is still a beautiful moment when a writer makes their debut.Your collection, ‘Transit for Beginners,’ due in March 2016, contains stories that you’ve placed in various litmags in India and outside. We are happy to inform our readers that the collection includes two stories that first appeared in TBLM; one of them is the story that gives the book its title.</description></item><item><title>कोई नज़्म लिखो – by Saurabh Jain</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/02/p414/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 12:49:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/02/p414/</guid><description>नज़्म लिखो , बेशुमार लिखो
पर उससे बदलाव की उम्मीद मत रखो
तुम्हे लगेगा तुमने बड़ी बात कह दी है
तुमने ही अगली क्रांति की नीव रख दी है
बस तुम्हारी इस नज़्म से अंधकार जल जाएगा
और अगले ही दिन सब बदल जाएगा
ये बातें बेशक सच्ची नहीं है,
और ये ग़लतफ़हमी भी अच्छी नहीं है
तुम्हारी नज़्म किसी पर्वत पे मामूली चोट की तरह है
किसी विशाल लोकतंत्र के एक वोट की तरह है</description></item><item><title>Lost Rickshaws – by Mihir Chitre</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/02/p412/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 12:47:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/02/p412/</guid><description>She says nothing, and how.
The radio plays a dirge
for December. Then when walking
was going from verse to worse
in the hay of our years, she infiltrated
the moonlight in my beers. My toothpaste
wasted on her charcoal lips.
The things I could do were few
and the things I couldn’t fewer.
The drugged street lamps; the lost
rickshaws in their long slumber. Now
she extends herself like a theorem</description></item><item><title>The Menace at the Gate – by Janet H. Swinney</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/02/p407/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 12:18:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/02/p407/</guid><description>Her period refused to come. She lay in turmoil beneath the ineffectual ceiling fan. No position brought relief from the heat. After days of tossing and turning and lying in limp sheets, her shoulders and her buttocks were disfigured by the blemishes served up by prickly heat, and the monsoon was still an age away.
Clans of mosquitoes infested the room, convening under the bed, as well as in the adjoining bathroom, where you took your pants down at your peril.</description></item></channel></rss>