<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2015/05 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/05/</link><description>Recent content in 2015/05 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/05/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>sketches</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/05/p325/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 14:51:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/05/p325/</guid><description>sisyphus at nizamuddin. the veiled sadness on a man’s face as he brings in one hand a bucket of dirty utensils, and in another the weight of the earth. sunlight drops on us like a curtain. the earth is spliced by a sunday. watch these men go about their lives the same way for years, the same day lived again and again for eternity.
she. began talking about her life to all and sundry.</description></item><item><title>Two Poems</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/05/p320/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 14:44:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/05/p320/</guid><description>**Hotel Lobby: Sultanahmet Istanbul
**
After the mosque and the church, some chestnuts,
after the rain— every drop a passport
to misery— we return to a room not housekept.
As we wait, we’re offered Turkish tea and Apple tea.
The family next to us is, we learn, from Germany.
Well, they’re Iraqis from Germany. We’re Indians
from America. But this evening, we’re all in the lobby
of a hotel in Sultanahmet: united against</description></item><item><title>Srinath Perur</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/05/p299/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 13:57:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/05/p299/</guid><description>We at TBLM have long felt the lack of a certain kind of conversation in the Indian literary discourse. There are interviews, yes, but these tend to be promotional in nature, and a writer generally makes appearances around a book launch. That is perhaps a necessity. But the writer interview, one that focuses on the process behind a book, its connection with the writer’s personality, her or his life before and after publication, her or his views about money, rewards and recognition in literary pursuits — is neither present nor being asked for.</description></item></channel></rss>