<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2013 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/</link><description>Recent content in 2013 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 11:44:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Absentee – by Rohini Manyam Seshasayee</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/12/p122/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 11:44:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/12/p122/</guid><description>Gauri sat nervously in the lobby of a high end salon, clutching the bridal package voucher that her mother had sent her with. A few minutes later, the receptionist let her know that the beautician was ready. Eyebrows would be dealt with first. The beautician held the ends of the thread in her mouth and hands, forming like intent scissors. Tears rolled down Gauri’s cheeks as her skin smarted and cooled her warm flushed cheeks.</description></item><item><title>Preexisting Conditions – by Richard Larson</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/10/p110/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 16:50:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/10/p110/</guid><description>“Are you ready to go?” Kristine asks, unballing a pair of her pantyhose. Jack shakes his dreadlocked head and scrabbles around in the ashtray. He comes up with a nug of weed between his fingers. He carries it like a saint’s toenail over to the table, to the improvised bong. Last night, after they fought, he sawed off a pop bottle and smoked too much.
“Give me some,” Kristine says, as he takes a rattling pull.</description></item><item><title>Exile – by Gabriel Valjan</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/09/p93/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 05:59:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/09/p93/</guid><description>Exile was first published in Issue 17 of &amp;gt;kill author.
**For my namesake
**
El desterrado es ese tipo de persona que ha perdido a su amante y busca en cada rostro nuevo el rostro querido y, siempre autoengañándose, piensa que lo ha encontrado.
The exile is the type of person who, having lost the Beloved, keeps searching for the face he loves in every new face and, forever deceiving himself, thinks he has found it.</description></item><item><title>Gasoline – by Jen Knox</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/09/p87/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 05:54:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/09/p87/</guid><description>My TV, computer and spare cash left with Laura. She’d visited her favorite shoe store with my Visa and used the back of the receipt to write a Dear Jude note. Her handwriting was precise. It explained that she would be moving to Arkansas to live with Gustav, some guy she met online, and would never be back. Looking at the receipt, I wondered if the two of them planned to open a store with all the shoes six-hundred dollars had bought.</description></item><item><title>Dream of the Butterfly – by Jigar Brahmbhatt</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/08/p78/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2013 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/08/p78/</guid><description>I am writing this. I want to keep writing something. I had started with something, thought of reaching somewhere. The tea is over, and it has managed to leave behind its stench in my breath. Cold is getting worse as evening is approaching…
I can’t write anymore. Few words here and there and I start getting disoriented.
So I look at her again. She is simple, there’s no applied glitter, but she radiates the magic of bygone days.</description></item><item><title>Transit for Beginners – by Rheea Mukherjee</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/08/p63/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 10:15:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/08/p63/</guid><description>I met him at Changi airport. After a seven hour flight from Tokyo, preceded by an eleven hour flight to Tokyo. My breath was stale and my deodorant had long since given up. Changi was a festival, packed with dazzling places to shop at and strange luxurious things to do. Showers with towel service, a spa, a movie theater, a twenty-four hour gym, and even a swimming pool in case the urge to swim struck while you were in between flights.</description></item><item><title>Amy and the Question of Before – by Mohit Parikh</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/07/p28/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 19:03:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/07/p28/</guid><description>_What do you do before you do?
_
This is a zen koan. I invented it. I was masturbating or was about to masturbate when I invented it. Actually, it is preposterously wrong to say I invented it. Nobody invents a koan, it just pops into your head. For more than an hour I grappled with mine, forgetting my sleepy dick, until I fell off the bed laughing so hard, so bodily, that all that was in my head got sucked up and dumped into my solar plexus like a sock into the pit of a heavy vacuum cleaner.</description></item><item><title>This Place can be Beautiful Again – by Alex Miller</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/06/p20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 09:53:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/06/p20/</guid><description>I sat by the river, on a damp log half-buried in mud, and watched how the yellow finger of water wound its way through the city, past gutters and factories and underneath bridges, and it smelled like the worst thing in the world. Whenever I read a poem or whatever about rivers, it’s always about the beauty and majesty of nature. I bet those writers never saw a river like this one.</description></item><item><title>Singapore Girl – by Nabina Das</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/06/p18/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 09:52:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/06/p18/</guid><description>(From Nabina Das’ soon-to-come short story collection “The House of Twining Roses – Stories of the Mapped and the Unmapped”, LiFi Publications)
When Sita stole those clothes, she was sure the old woman wouldn’t know. It was a whim anyway. Sita always did things out of whims. I’m not that type. Rather, the supportive kind. Besides, I didn’t see myself as a thief. I just gave her company. We were friends.</description></item><item><title>Mother – by Jigar Brahmbhatt</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/06/p15/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 09:41:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2013/06/p15/</guid><description>Her absence is the kitchen’s lack of aroma. Back in the day, what seemed to bind their lives from one day to the next was the sweet spicy smell that wafted from the kitchen every morning. There was something inexplicable about it. Spreading from one room to another, it used to fill their home with a sort of life-affirmation. It gave them an unconscious hope that someone was there. That someone had already greeted dawn before they broke their slumber.</description></item></channel></rss>