<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>9 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/issue/9/</link><description>Recent content in 9 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:21:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/issue/9/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The American</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/01/p254/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:21:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/01/p254/</guid><description>_The story was first published in UpRightDown; also anthologized in Best of the Web 2009, edited by Lee K. Abbott
_
They lunch at L’olivier, and during her first glass A– says, There was a tourist. Of course there was, D– chides, her disgust for tourists as palpable as the crème brûlée she abuses with her spoon. Was he good in bed, at least? C– asks. Except for the swearing, A– says, yes.</description></item><item><title>No Town for Love</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/01/p252/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:15:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/01/p252/</guid><description>While a smooth curving flyover on the national highway cleanly bypassed the town of Moradabad, if one had to go there, it had to be with purpose. The unending markets on either side of the congested roads screamed with the clamor of commerce. Motor workshops jostled easily with shops processing grain and pulses, gur and khandsari . Ancient eateries frying jalebis and kachauris vied to generate more heat and smell than the myriad brass metal units outflanking them.</description></item><item><title>Keeping Pace</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/01/p249/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:10:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/01/p249/</guid><description>I was the first woman in his life, she, the most recent. Apart from him, the other thing we had in common was running. I’d finished one full and three half marathons. She was attempting her first 10k. The type of distance that becomes an accessory. She was the type of artist that makes a living out of being one. Her 10k goal was an urban layer of achievement that adds nicely to a personality.</description></item></channel></rss>