<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2020/01 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2020/01/</link><description>Recent content in 2020/01 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2020/01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Top Ten Mining Terms You Should Know – by Mandira Pattnaik</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2020/01/p982/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 08:39:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2020/01/p982/</guid><description>#10 bench: floor; usage: On the horizontal bench1050 was the muck—black mounds of illegal coal, and several pie tins clustered in one corner. All them, underground savages, crawled down to depths of upto 4000ft. in the abandoned mine, northern panhandle, Western Meghalaya, through labyrinthine passages dug with basic mining implements—shovels, hammers, pickaxes, and chisels. Its black roof and ribs—dark dungeons really—dripped water, like milk from a bovine’s udder. A slip gets them an instant burial in a watery grave.</description></item><item><title>A Family Affair – by Anand Jacob</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2020/01/p979/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 08:27:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2020/01/p979/</guid><description>“This depraved lifestyle is no good, Cattaparthy,” said a voice, and Cattaparthy opened an eye, reconsidered, and shut it again.
“Fergof merber,” he said.
The visitor, a slim tuxedo cat, sipped from a glass, and tutted.
“You won’t last two years. This stuff is not bad at all,” said the cat, sniffing the glass’s amber contents.
“Wharg,” said Cattaparthy.
Cupping a hand to his ear, the visitor said: “Even early in the afternoon, so profound,” he said.</description></item><item><title>The Goddess Who Wants Out – by Kritika Pandey</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2020/01/p976/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 08:11:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2020/01/p976/</guid><description>You and I first met on a narrow hospital bed, lying side by side, astounded by the world as well as by each other. Our parents were not friends, just friendly next-door neighbors who were excited at us being born a few days apart in the same hospital. I have often wondered if they switched one baby girl for another in their excitement, if we are living each other’s lives. In our photographs from the maternity ward, we are cocooned in soft blue fabrics with a disinfected white bedsheet behind us, looking like two neelkanth birds against a cloudy afternoon sky, or, as you once put it, fake fuckin’ menstrual blood on TV.</description></item><item><title>Waiting Room – by Angana Sinha Ray</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2020/01/p963/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 04:23:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2020/01/p963/</guid><description>‘Do not be afraid of making mistakes on paper.’
The cursor blinks in apathy. Hot white lights; cold steel trolleys gliding across the polished marble floor in clean diagonals like a carrom board. The lobby swallows sober men infected with orderly panic. There’s a high roof but no room for talk. Some men disappear behind the revolving glass door that creaks in protest every time a person enters. The slight swirl fills the lobby up with a smell Shibani knows too well.</description></item><item><title>Urvashi Bahuguna – interviewed by Sharanya Manivannan</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2020/01/p960/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 04:05:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2020/01/p960/</guid><description>Terrarium opens on a poem about girls who “had the world at the instep of their sole”, encouraged to run like they mean it by Mr. Joseph, who treated them like he did the boys. It seems to capture so much about what this collection is about: girls and women, connection to the (literal, muddy) earth, the speed and sudden shifts in life’s trajectories. It’s also about a specific person, a teacher, and the effect he had on these girls.</description></item><item><title>Three prose poems – by Poornima Laxmeshwar</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2020/01/p958/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 03:49:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2020/01/p958/</guid><description>Living a dog’s life
On the day of Divasi amavasya, Amma breaks a thumri on the transistor, fetches some fresh mud near the tulsi plant with a girl child’s innocence. She makes two idols — Shiva and Parvati — faceless, crude, even genderless. She empties a bowl of coconut oil on my head, saying that my head is hot, and scrubs it with shikakai she has brought all the way from Bangalore.</description></item></channel></rss>