<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>interviews on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/category/interviews/</link><description>Recent content in interviews on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 04:05:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/category/interviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Urvashi Bahuguna – interviewed by Sharanya Manivannan</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2020/01/p960/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 04:05:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2020/01/p960/</guid><description>Terrarium opens on a poem about girls who “had the world at the instep of their sole”, encouraged to run like they mean it by Mr. Joseph, who treated them like he did the boys. It seems to capture so much about what this collection is about: girls and women, connection to the (literal, muddy) earth, the speed and sudden shifts in life’s trajectories. It’s also about a specific person, a teacher, and the effect he had on these girls.</description></item><item><title>Sharanya Manivannan – interviewed by Tanuj Solanki [2]</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/02/p687/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 17:37:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2018/02/p687/</guid><description>We first interviewed Sharanya Manivannan after the publication of her short story collection, The High Priestess Never Marries_. That interview can be read here. This interview was done in the light of her recent poetry collection,_ The Altar of the Only World.
**The world ‘Only’ in your title: should we pause on it? Sita, Inanna, Sita-Inanna – they reach the underworld in your poems. Yet this underworld is not the world being referred to as the only world, and is certainly not the world where the feast (let’s say the one in the poem ‘Benediction for the Feast’) eventually takes place.</description></item><item><title>Deepti Kapoor – interviewed by Michelle D’Costa</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/05/p542/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 06:10:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2017/05/p542/</guid><description>This interview was conducted by e-mail. It is about Deepti Kapoor’s novel A Bad Character, first published by Penguin Random House, 2014.
About the novel (from Goodreads)
A highly charged fiction debut about a young woman in India, and the love that both shatters and transforms her. She is twenty, restless in New Delhi. Her mother has died; her father has left for Singapore. He is a few years older, just back to India from New York.</description></item><item><title>Sharanya Manivannan – interviewed by Tanuj Solanki</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/12/p522/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 15:42:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/12/p522/</guid><description>Barring a couple of stories, the protagonists in your stories can be said to be in stasis. They end where they begin; or if there is a change, it serves only to make them more conscious of their conflicts, paradoxes. Thought of from a technical viewpoint, stasis is the enemy of plot. What are your views on this thing called plot? How comfortable are you with it, and will we ever see you write a traditionally—for want of a better word—plotted work?</description></item><item><title>Rheea Mukherjee — interviewed by TBLM Staff</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/03/p434/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 08:27:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2016/03/p434/</guid><description>**First of all, let me congratulate you on compiling a collection of short stories. It is still a beautiful moment when a writer makes their debut.Your collection, ‘Transit for Beginners,’ due in March 2016, contains stories that you’ve placed in various litmags in India and outside. We are happy to inform our readers that the collection includes two stories that first appeared in TBLM; one of them is the story that gives the book its title.</description></item><item><title>Anees Salim – interviewed by TBLM Staff</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/09/p358/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 15:38:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/09/p358/</guid><description>Anees Salim is one of the most prominent and critically acclaimed novelists in India today. He has published four novels, namely The Vicks Mango Tree, Tales From A Vending Machine, Vanity Bagh, and The Blind Lady’s Descendants. Of these, Vanity Bagh won the The Hindu Literary Prize in 2013 and The Blind Lady’s Descendants won the Crossword Book Award for English Fiction 2014.
Salim’s narrators retain a straight-faced sense of humour in the face of great personal tragedy and sometimes perform the function of social commentary, the latter never out of any sense of solutionism or false idealism.</description></item><item><title>Srinath Perur – interviewed by Mohit Parikh</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/05/p299/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 13:57:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2015/05/p299/</guid><description>We at TBLM have long felt the lack of a certain kind of conversation in the Indian literary discourse. There are interviews, yes, but these tend to be promotional in nature, and a writer generally makes appearances around a book launch. That is perhaps a necessity. But the writer interview, one that focuses on the process behind a book, its connection with the writer’s personality, her or his life before and after publication, her or his views about money, rewards and recognition in literary pursuits — is neither present nor being asked for.</description></item></channel></rss>