<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2014 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/</link><description>Recent content in 2014 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 05:21:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2014: Year in Reading</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/12/p244/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 05:21:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/12/p244/</guid><description>Our contributors are our aesthetic.
TBLM did the exercise of asking its contributors to write back with a couple of their favorite books read in 2014. We basically asked for the books that really made a difference for them this year. Some responded, and voila, now we have an awesome TBR list for all you readers.
**Rheea Mukherjee
**
BobCat and Other stories by Rebecca Lee, because it gives me faith in the modern short story.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Mohit Parikh’s ‘Manan’</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/12/p227/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 15:18:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/12/p227/</guid><description>Manan
by Mohit Parikh
Harper, 2014
Rs. 199
A Review
Mihir Vatsa
To Start With,
He closes his eyes and finds today’s date floating towards him. Shimmering in the darkness, swiveling— like the text on the Windows 95 screensaver. It seeps in through his forehead and gets absorbed. 23-04-98 is now a part of him. Today’s date, a Saturday, when the first sign of what he so eagerly awaited has appeared.</description></item><item><title>The Faraway Things</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/07/p192/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 12:25:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/07/p192/</guid><description>A Piki Tup garbage van rattles past Kero as she winces at the four-inch face of her phone. The familiar odour of rotting trash wafts into her nostrils. She frowns, looks up, curbs an urge to spit, then down again. She quickly finds her place in the text message she is re-reading. It confounds her even more. She wishes the bus would come already. With the exception of the one time she had missed it, the five o’clock bus to Highlands North had never been on time.</description></item><item><title>The Balance in Silence</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/07/p189/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 04:25:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/07/p189/</guid><description>I watch the tide of a new morning in the pallor of the curtains against the pane of the bedroom window. Except for the birds on the mango tree outside and an occasional vehicle that honks on the stray dogs, there is no sound.
Nothing has changed while we slept.
A morning person, I look with disappointment at Tina, the wife I once loved. The wife I am trying to love again.</description></item><item><title>Equal</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/06/p184/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 16:26:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/06/p184/</guid><description>Equal
between amber
and blue eyes
seven warriors of
thistle
and heat of the sun
as three hummingbirds
in your eyelashes.
***</description></item><item><title>The Infinite Capacity for Illusion</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/03/p162/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 20:28:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/03/p162/</guid><description>Whither The Magic?
One Hundred Years of Solitude is one of my favorite novels. Which is why, when I started reading Love in the Time of Cholera, one of the things I noticed immediately was the lack of that subtle brand of magic that I had so enjoyed. I wanted it badly and went around every corner with the expectation of a cheerful reunion. But it was not to be.</description></item></channel></rss>