<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2014 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/</link><description>Recent content in 2014 on The Bombay Literary Magazine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 05:21:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2014: Year in Reading</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/12/p244/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 05:21:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/12/p244/</guid><description>Our contributors are our aesthetic.
TBLM did the exercise of asking its contributors to write back with a couple of their favorite books read in 2014. We basically asked for the books that really made a difference for them this year. Some responded, and voila, now we have an awesome TBR list for all you readers.
**Rheea Mukherjee
**
BobCat and Other stories by Rebecca Lee, because it gives me faith in the modern short story.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Mohit Parikh’s ‘Manan’ – by Mihir Vatsa</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/12/p227/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 15:18:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/12/p227/</guid><description>Manan
by Mohit Parikh
Harper, 2014
Rs. 199
A Review
Mihir Vatsa
To Start With,
He closes his eyes and finds today’s date floating towards him. Shimmering in the darkness, swiveling— like the text on the Windows 95 screensaver. It seeps in through his forehead and gets absorbed. 23-04-98 is now a part of him. Today’s date, a Saturday, when the first sign of what he so eagerly awaited has appeared.</description></item><item><title>Because If Nothing Matters – by Jigar Brahmbhatt</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/12/p225/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 13:43:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/12/p225/</guid><description>It didn’t occur to me till much later that Joe had stopped coming to the library. I used to go to the British Council library regularly, and had chatted with him a couple of times. Now I had often met curious people before but he was the most eccentric among the lot. The kind that spend whole afternoons amidst stacks not because they like being surrounded by books, but because they have nowhere else to go.</description></item><item><title>Hope That He Hears – by Prashila Naik</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/12/p221/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 16:39:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/12/p221/</guid><description>You are secretly in love with your cousin. Every vacation, in your grandmother’s house, you watch him grow a few more inches, and of late display a few more sprouts of hair. You marvel at how his voice is better than that of any boy you have heard. You also marvel at how he can sing English songs you have never heard before. Every time he touches your palm, in an attempt to teach you the right way to strike on the carrom board, you struggle to control your smile, and struggle to control the spreading of a warm, fuzzy feeling that honestly leaves you baffled.</description></item><item><title>The Tourist – by Aravind Jayan</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/10/p213/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 04:53:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/10/p213/</guid><description>The line outside the lunch hall was far too long- out of the weather worn tarpaulin it went, curving at oblique points of chatter and conversation, scattering into a thicket of small and smaller children, and finally into a throng of ladies all clad in starched shades of gold, green or red; men were scant, the few around the marriage hall could be seen walking about nestling half empty bottles of aquafina or nippled bottles of pale warm milk.</description></item><item><title>Fault – by Gaurav Deka</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/08/p208/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 12:43:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/08/p208/</guid><description>During the days we met, the rains were light. The mushrooms behind the house had weeded brown and you had said how sitting by them I looked like the boy who came out of water in a certain book you had read recently. On Fridays, you came early with a polythene packet knit gently around your wrist, dangling.
“Baruahs sold out for the day. Just the last two. Lucky! Aren’t we?</description></item><item><title>Hobby – by Bhumika Anand</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/08/p198/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 18:04:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/08/p198/</guid><description>What Girish knew about having sex with a woman came from spending hours studying his grandfather, the old watchmaker, repair old clocks.
Around the time that Girish turned 16, he found that the process of mending something broken and allowing something to chime again fascinated him more than even cricket. There was something soothing about his grandfather’s painstaking ways of repairing watches and clocks. He decided to study how his grandfather repaired time pieces and the study soon turned into a hobby.</description></item><item><title>The Faraway Things – by Kushinga Kambarami</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/07/p192/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 12:25:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/07/p192/</guid><description>A Piki Tup garbage van rattles past Kero as she winces at the four-inch face of her phone. The familiar odour of rotting trash wafts into her nostrils. She frowns, looks up, curbs an urge to spit, then down again. She quickly finds her place in the text message she is re-reading. It confounds her even more. She wishes the bus would come already. With the exception of the one time she had missed it, the five o’clock bus to Highlands North had never been on time.</description></item><item><title>The Balance in Silence – by Kulpreet Yadav</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/07/p189/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 04:25:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/07/p189/</guid><description>I watch the tide of a new morning in the pallor of the curtains against the pane of the bedroom window. Except for the birds on the mango tree outside and an occasional vehicle that honks on the stray dogs, there is no sound.
Nothing has changed while we slept.
A morning person, I look with disappointment at Tina, the wife I once loved. The wife I am trying to love again.</description></item><item><title>Equal – by Lepota L. Cosmo</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/06/p184/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 16:26:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/06/p184/</guid><description>Equal
between amber
and blue eyes
seven warriors of
thistle
and heat of the sun
as three hummingbirds
in your eyelashes.
***</description></item><item><title>The Last Show – by Dion D’Souza</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/05/p174/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 11:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/05/p174/</guid><description>It is quite possible that I took a wrong turn as I was walking down the quiet, dark corridor, fumbling my way out of the building. There was no one behind me, though in all likelihood, that was because most of the other patrons (there had been just a handful in attendance to begin with) had chosen to take the exit to the left. I do not usually watch movies at this theatre, but it was the only one in the vicinity screening this film, and because I very much wanted to watch it, I had travelled here not entirely out of choice.</description></item><item><title>The Help – by Michelle D’Costa</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/04/p166/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 14:40:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/04/p166/</guid><description>She aroused interest in Bradley like a sealed envelope could do.
He was dumb but not deaf and she did not know that.
When she realised he was dumb she assumed that he had to be deaf too.
She was the help but she was not hired to look after him.
Little did she know that to him the sounds of her washing the dishes were a melody of their own.</description></item><item><title>The Infinite Capacity for Illusion – by Riku Sayuj</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/03/p162/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 20:28:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/03/p162/</guid><description>Whither The Magic?
One Hundred Years of Solitude is one of my favorite novels. Which is why, when I started reading Love in the Time of Cholera, one of the things I noticed immediately was the lack of that subtle brand of magic that I had so enjoyed. I wanted it badly and went around every corner with the expectation of a cheerful reunion. But it was not to be.</description></item><item><title>An Amorphous Voyage of Fleeting Seeds – by Rahul Shingrani</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/01/p152/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 12:53:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/01/p152/</guid><description>Life came to us at that cusp of infinite void, the edge of the sun’s reach. It was a sudden awakening, though awakening might mean that we had been sleeping, been alive. We were never alive, both Kreetin and I.
Till the time our star-hopping vessel passed the heliosphere at the edge of solar system, we existed in not a deep slumber, but as lifeless crud. The understanding of all of humanity flashed onto us in a blinding instant, a drip bang boom of knowledge quicker than an antsy sneeze.</description></item><item><title>The Mummy’s Bitter And Melancholy Exile – by Norman Lock</title><link>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/01/p129/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 07:29:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.evalapply.org/tblm-public/posts/2014/01/p129/</guid><description>_The story was first published in Cranky Literary Journal, and subsequently appeared in Lock’s newest short story collection, Love Among the Particles, published in May, 2013, by Bellevue Literary Press, New York City.
_
_Osiris, God of the Dead
_
The Mummy is invited to speak on the radio. He is driven from his apartment house through the autumn streets, toward the broadcasting studio. He looks through the limousine window at the street-cleaners sweeping the fallen leaves.</description></item></channel></rss>